(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
MINATO AQUA
4th ANNIVERSARY
SPECIAL LIVE
あくあ色ふぇすてぃばる。
Aqua-Iro Festival.
あてし 湊あくあ
I'm Minato Aqua,
職業スーパーウルトラ何でもパーフェクトなメイドさん！
a super ultra everything-perfect maid!
今日もご主人様のために精一杯頑張っちゃうぞー！
I'll do my absolute best for Master again today!
ラブ・ラブ ラブ・ラブ メイドさんだぞ イェイ！
Love-love, love-love, I'm a maid, yay!
あくたんのこと好きすぎ☆ソング
The "I Love Akutan Too Much" Song
みんな、ありがとー！
Everyone, thank you!
自信満々メイドはてんてこ舞い
A confident maid is in a whirl
お掃除、洗濯 ほら、汗だくだ
Cleaning, laundry, look, I'm dripping with sweat
お料理こげたな てへぺろ
The food's burnt, tee-hee
許して ご主人！
Forgive me, Master!
ゲームばかりして怒られてる
Getting scolded for just playing games
プリティー猫フェイスで誤魔化すにゃ
Faking it with a pretty cat face, nya
お昼寝はメイドの性
Napping is a maid's nature
ご機嫌な夢見て すやすや
Having happy dreams, sleeping soundly
エプロンパタパタ 本気メイド！
Flapping apron, serious maid!
トイレはいかないよ アイドルメイド！
I don't go to the bathroom, idol maid!
あ、ご主人 にやついてる！
Ah, Master is grinning!
ダメ、ダメ！
No, no!
メイド服 脱いだら
If I take off my maid uniform
忠実な 女の子に戻るけど
I go back to being a loyal girl, but
ご主人様との思い出 作れますか？
Can we make memories together, Master?
ずっと仲良くしてね
Let's always get along
鼻先見ないで シワになっちゃうよ
Don't look at the tip of my nose, it'll get wrinkled
思い出してくれるよね この...
You'll remember me, won't you? This...
チュッ！
Chu!
オムライス！
Omelet rice!
みんなあてしのこと好きすぎ！
Everyone loves me too much!
奔放メイドは年中無休
A free-spirited maid is open all year round
朝から晩までやることだらけ
Tons of things to do from morning till night
歌って踊ってドタバタ
Singing and dancing, pitter-patter
構ってご主人！
Pay attention to me, Master!
寝坊は数えないけど
I don't count the times I overslept, but
猫耳の手も借りて 頑張るにゃ
I'll do my best with a little help, nya
お帰りなさい ご主人様
Welcome home, Master
たまにはサービス いいでしょ？
A little service once in a while is okay, right?
ゲームに負けたら 号泣メイド！
Crybaby maid if I lose at games!
甘やかしてくれたら お仕置きメイド！
Punishment maid if you spoil me!
あれ、ご主人 怒っちゃった？
Oh, is Master angry?
やだ、やだ！
No, no!
メイド服を着たら
When I wear my maid uniform
普通の女の子になれるかな...
I wonder if I can be a normal girl...
ずっとそばで笑っていたいな　遊びたいな
I want to keep smiling by your side, I want to play
ずっと仲良くしてね
Stay on good terms with me forever, okay?
（Yeah!）
(Yeah!)
星降る夜に　魔法をかけちゃいましょう
On this starry night, let's cast a spell
いたずらだってご愛嬌でしょ
Even mischief is just part of my charm, right?
（Fu-fu!）
(Fu-fu!)
上目遣い
An upward glance
（Hey!）
(Hey!)
イチコロでしょ
You'll fall for me in an instant
（Wow!）
(Wow!)
おかえり、ご主人！
Welcome home, Master!
お砂糖お醤油間違えちゃった
I mixed up the sugar and soy sauce
ご飯？お風呂？それともあ・く・あ？
Dinner? A bath? Or... A-ku-a?
メイドからメイド　メイドなんです！
From maid to maid, I'm a maid!
お茶は苦手　水ならOK！
I'm not good with tea, water is OK!
こたつでカニ鍋やっぱ鍋！
Crab hot pot in the kotatsu, gotta have hot pot!
壊れたテレビは叩けば直る！
A broken TV can be fixed by hitting it!
低気圧やば！一生寝てよ
Low pressure is awful! Let's sleep forever
お隣さん　お向かいさん
Neighbors, people across the street
世界のみなさん　お前さん
Everyone in the world, and you
銀河一のラブを込めて　いくよ
Sending you the best love in the galaxy, here I go
せーの！
Ready, set...
おいしくな～れ！萌え萌えキュン！
Become delicious! Moe moe kyun!
泣いて　凹んで　笑って
Crying, feeling down, laughing
夢を追いかけています
I'm chasing my dreams
おとぎ話だと言わせないよ
I won't let anyone say it's just a fairy tale
ずっと私を見ててね
Keep watching me forever
恋をしちゃったら消えちゃうマーメイド
A mermaid who disappears if she falls in love
重たくなったらごめんね
Sorry if things get too heavy
でも！
But!
（Oh-wow!）　トモダチじゃないもん
(Oh-wow!) We're not just friends!
メイド服脱げたら　ただの女の子だけど
When I take off my maid uniform, I'm just an ordinary girl
あなたとの思い出作れますか？
Can I make memories with you?
ずっと仲良くしてね
Stay on good terms with me forever
（Yeah!）
(Yeah!)
他の誰かを見ないで
Don't look at anyone else
しわくちゃになっちゃったって
Even if we get all wrinkled
思い出してね　この
Please remember this
（Oh-wow!）　オムライス
(Oh-wow!) Omelet rice
全部食べて！
Eat it all!
なんちゃって
Just kidding!
（Wahhh!）
(Wahhh!)
月曜日は身体が動きません
My body won't move on Mondays
っていうか毎日でした　ピリピリ偏頭痛
Actually, it's every day, a tingling migraine
私ったらメイドの個性的料理ダメ
I'm a maid but bad at unique cooking
掃除もちょっとアレ　てんてこまいでまいった
Cleaning is also a bit... I'm overwhelmed and troubled
お醤油あるのみですね
I only have soy sauce
Hey you 会いたくなってしまったな
Hey you, I've started wanting to see you
今夜も
Tonight as well
ヨナヨナ集まって何する？
Gathering night after night, what shall we do?
月火水木金土日365日24時間画面越しご挨拶
Mon-Tue-Wed-Thu-Fri-Sat-Sun, 365 days, 24 hours, greeting through the screen
せーの！
Ready, set...
好きになっちゃって言っちゃって全然可愛くない
I fell in love and said it, not cute at all
（ない！）
(Not!)
勝手に凹んだって泣いてみたって全然可愛くない
Feeling down on my own, trying to cry, not cute at all
君だって同じ　ダメよりの事由です
You're the same, a reason for being no good
そんな優しくして　私に気があるのかな？
Being so kind, I wonder if you have feelings for me?
もうこんな時間どんな予感神ハプニング
It's already this time, what a feeling, a divine happening
亜中毒症状急上昇MAXメンタル崩壊
Aqua addiction symptoms skyrocketing MAX mental breakdown
あなたのことをもっともっと知りたい
I want to know more and more about you
水曜日は意識がレボリューション
Wednesdays, my consciousness undergoes a revolution
っていうか毎日でした　ピリピリ偏頭痛
Actually, it's every day, a tingling migraine
私ったら競争社会不適合者
I'm a misfit for this competitive society
でも挙動は適合者のふりして暴言吐いて
But I pretend to be a fit behavior-wise while spitting out insults
凹んだこれって法廷事後？
Fell down, is this a post-court matter?
Hey you 会いたくなってしまったな
Hey you, I've started wanting to see you
今夜も
Tonight as well
自家警備からの脱却
Escape from home security
頑張れ私　負けるな
Hang in there, me! Don't give up!
せーの！
Ready, set...
好きになっちゃって言っちゃって全然可愛くない
I fell in love and said it, not cute at all
（ない！）
(Not!)
勝手に凹んだって泣いてみたって全然可愛くない
Feeling down on my own, trying to cry, not cute at all
君だって同じ　ダメよりの事由です
You're the same, a reason for being no good
そんな優しくして　私に気があるのかな？
Being so kind, I wonder if you have feelings for me?
もうこんな時間どんな予感神ハプニング
It's already this time, what a feeling, a divine happening
亜中毒症状急上昇MAXメンタル崩壊
Aqua addiction symptoms skyrocketing MAX mental breakdown
あなたのことをもっともっと知りたい
I want to know more and more about you
あー　特別じゃない
Ah, it's not special
私のこと　勘違いして
Misunderstand me
馬鹿ね
You fool
馴れ合いこそが
Familiarity itself is
君と僕を繋ぐ光
The light that connects you and me
今日は4周年ライブに遊びに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my 4th anniversary live today!
もう4周年ってマジ！？
Wait, 4th anniversary already? For real!?
いっぱいゲストも出るから、よかったら最後まで見てね！
Lots of guests are coming, so please watch until the end!
月水木金土日さあ 365日
Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Sunday, 365 days
画面越しを 愛さす
Loving through the screen...
怖くない せーの！
Not scary! Ready, go!
好きになっちゃって 言っちゃったって 全然可愛くない
Falling in love, saying it out loud, not cute at all
勝手に凹んだって 泣いてみたって 全然可愛くない
Feeling down, trying to cry, not cute at all
君だっておんなじ 鏡の中の自分です
You're the same, you're the person in the mirror
どんだけ優しくするの？私だってちょっと好きなの！
How kind are you going to be? I like you a little bit too!
もうこんな時間 どんな予感 神ハプニング
It's already this time, what a premonition, divine happening
中毒症状 挑んでマックス メンタル崩壊
Addiction symptoms, challenging to the max, mental breakdown
あなたのことをもっともっと知りたい
I want to know more and more about you
あなたのことを…
About you...
まだあなたのことを何も知らない
I still don't know anything about you
Kiss me baby
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ありがとう！ 2曲続けてお聞きいただきました！
Thank you! You just heard two songs back-to-back!
あくたんのこと好きすぎソング、そして あいわな でした！ ありがとうー！
That was 'Akutan no Koto Suki Sugi Song' and 'Ai Wana'! Thank you!
ということで、あく好き、なんかめっちゃ合いの手いたけどね！
So, in 'Akusuki', there were a lot of chants!
なんか賑やかな感じになってたけど、
It felt really lively,
みんなもコメントでちゃんと合いの手してくれた？
but did everyone do the chants in the comments too?
じゃあ一回ちょっと聞くから、みんなね、あのコメントしてください。
So, I'll listen for a moment, everyone, please comment.
いくよ？
Ready?
あくたんのことー？
Akutan is...?
好きすぎー！
Loved too much!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much. Thank you very much.
ということで、なんと4周年！わぁー！
And so, it's our 4th anniversary! Wow!
4周年ライブですよ。もう4周年ですか。
It's the 4th anniversary live. Has it really been 4 years?
あくあ色ふぇすてぃばる。ということで、
It's the 'Aqua-iro Festival'.
ま、フェスティバルと言うからにはお祭りのような、
Since it's a 'festival', it's like a celebration.
なんかね、たくさんのゲストがこの先出る予感がしますが、
I have a feeling many guests will appear later on,
とりあえずはね、ま、4周年ということで、
but for now, it's the 4th anniversary,
皆さんね、ここまで湊あくあね、応援してくれて本当にありがとうございます！
and I want to thank everyone for supporting Minato Aqua all this way!
ありがとう！ ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
いや、本当、私はね、めちゃめちゃ本当、こう未熟なね、
Really, I'm... really immature,
すごいね、本当、皆さんに助けていただいてばかりで、
and I'm always being helped by everyone.
ホロメンのみんなもそうだし、マネージャーさんもそうだし、スタッフの皆さんもそうだし、
That goes for my fellow Holo-members, my managers, and the staff,
何よりもみんなに、なんか助けてもらって支えてもらってばかりだけど、
and above all, you guys. I'm always being helped and supported by everyone.
いやー、なんか感慨深いよ。
Man, it's really moving.
ね、こうして、なんか、4年前はね、
You know, 4 years ago,
こう、4周年ってなったときに想像してみたんだけど、
I tried to imagine what it would be like when it became the 4th anniversary,
なんか4年前、私デビューしたときまさかこうしてね、
but 4 years ago, when I debuted, I never thought I'd be here like this,
こういうフェスティバルとか言ってたくさんのゲストとともに、
holding a 'festival' with so many guests,
こんな可愛い衣装を着て、歌って踊れるなんて思ってなかったし、
wearing such a cute outfit, singing and dancing.
ね、初めての3D配信はね、この前見返した、見返したんだけど、
You know, I re-watched my first 3D stream the other day,
本当にね、なんかアイドルらしからぬ、なんか前転とかやってたよ、前転。
and really, it was anything but idol-like... I was doing forward rolls and stuff.
でね、あのね、骨が折れてた。
And, you know, my bones were breaking.
ちょっと黒歴史に近いけど、
It's almost a dark past for me,
本当に、なんか、あのときもちょっと、なんか頑張って踊ってたけど、
but really, even then I was trying my best to dance.
あの頃とはね、比べ物にならないくらいね、ダンスが上達しました！
Compared to back then, my dancing has improved so much!
上達しました！
It really has!
もうね、なんか運動不足、運動神経の悪い人の動きだとは、
I won't let anyone say I move like someone who's out of shape
言わせない、言わせない、言わせ、言わせないぞ！
or lacks athletic ability anymore!
え？ どうかな？ 結構さらなり軽やかに行けてるでしょ？ でしょ？
Eh? What do you think? I'm moving quite smoothly and lightly, right? Right?
ということでね、え、4周年で成長もありだけど、ね、
So, even after 4 years, there's been growth, and...
たくさんの成長もありますけど、
a lot of growth indeed, but...
未だにね、運動不足ではありますけど、運動神経はね、やっぱり悪いなと思いますけど、
I'm still out of shape, and I think my athletic ability is still bad, but...
4年目もどうぞ皆さん、よろしくお願いします！
please continue to support me in my 4th year as well!
ということで、それではここからゲストパート行きたいと思います！
So, it's time to move on to the guest part!
その前に！
But before that!
なんとこんな、あ、このアリス衣装のままじゃちょっと、
If I stay in this Alice outfit,
なんかさ、浮いちゃうかなって思って、
I think I might look a bit out of place,
ちょっと今から大変身するから見ててね！
so I'm going to transform right now, so watch closely!
変ーー身！！
Trans-form!!
パッ！
Ta-da!
わーい！ ということでいつものアイドル衣装にチェンジしたということで！
Yay! So, I've changed into my usual idol outfit!
それではここから...
Now, from here...
ここからはゲストがどんどん出てくるので、お楽しみに！
From here on, guests will be appearing one after another, so look forward to it!
うおおおおおお！！！
Wooooooo!!!
常闇トワ
Tokoyami Towa
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
湊あくあ
Minato Aqua
NEXT SONG
三原色
湊あくあ 星街すいせい 常闇トワ
Sangenshoku
Minato Aqua, Hoshimachi Suisei, Tokoyami Towa
どこかで途切れた物語
A story that was cut off somewhere
僕らもう一度その先へ
We're heading beyond that once more
たとえ何度離れてしまってもほら
Even if we're separated many times, look
繋がっている
We're connected
それじゃまたね 交わした言葉
"See ya then," the words we exchanged
あれから幾つ朝日を見たんだ
How many sunrises have I seen since then?
それぞれの暮らしの先で
At the end of our respective lives
あの日の続き 再会の日
The continuation of that day, the day of our reunion
待ち合わせまでの時間がただ
The time until our meeting just
過ぎてゆく度に胸が高鳴る
The more it passes, the more my heart beats faster
雨上がりの空見上げれば
When I look up at the sky after the rain
あの日と同じように
Just like that day
架かる七色の橋
A seven-colored bridge hangs
ここでもう一度出会えたんだよ
We were able to meet here once more
僕ら繋がっていたんだずっと
We've been connected all along
話したいこと 伝えたいこと
Things I want to talk about, things I want to convey
溢れて止まらないから
They're overflowing and won't stop
ほら ほどけてゆく
Look, they're unraveling
巡る季節に急かされて
Hurried by the turning seasons
続く道のその先また
Further ahead on the continuing path
離れたってさ 何度だってさ
Even if we part, any number of times
強く結び直したなら また会える
If we tie our bonds strongly again, we'll meet again
変わってしまったことだって
Even things that have changed
本当はきっと幾つもある
Truthfully, I'm sure there are many
だけど
But
今日だってあけないほどあの頃のままで
Even today, it's just like those days, as if they never ended
気付けば空は白み始め
Before I knew it, the sky began to turn white
疲れ果てた僕らの背後に
Behind our exhausted selves
触れる陽の光 温かさ
The sunlight touching us, the warmth
あの日と同じように
Just like that day
それぞれの日常に帰る
Returning to our respective daily lives
ねえここまで歩いてきた道は
Hey, the path we've walked so far
それぞれ違うけれど
Is different for each of us, but
同じ朝日に今照らされてる
We're being shone upon by the same morning sun now
また重なり合えたんだ
We were able to overlap once again
どこかで途切れた物語
A story that was cut off somewhere
僕らもう一度その先へ
We're heading beyond that once more
話したいこと 伝えたいこと
Things I want to talk about, things I want to convey
ページを埋めてゆくように
As if filling up the pages
ほら 書き足そうよ 何度でも
Look, let's add to it, as many times as it takes
いつか見上げた赤い夕日も
The red sunset we looked up at one day
共に過ごした青い月日も
The blue days we spent together
忘れないから 消えやしないから
I won't forget them, they won't disappear
緑が芽吹くように また会えるから
Like the green sprouting, because we can meet again
物語は白い朝日から始まる
The story begins with the white morning sun
また明日
See you tomorrow
はーい！ということで！Startendの二人が来てくれましたー！
Hi~! So! Both of Startend have come!
イエーイ！
Yeah!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
おとといぶり。
It's been since the day before yesterday.
おとといぶりだ、そうだ。
The day before yesterday, that's right.
おとといっていうのか？おとといぶりか。
Do you call it the day before yesterday? Since the day before yesterday.
おととい…あれ？なんかさー…
The day before yesterday... huh? It's like...
「また会えたんだね」とか言ってさ、実はもう会ってましたみたいな…
We said things like "We were able to meet again," but actually we'd already met...
さっき会ってたみたいなね。
Like we just met a while ago.
すみません、さっきまで。
Sorry, just until a moment ago.
でも、エモかった。エモかったことだ。
But it was emotional. It was an emotional thing.
そうだそうだ。
True, true.
ね、あくたんの記念日とトワのちょっと周年祭がね、同じということで！
Right, Akutan's anniversary and Towa's anniversary festival are the same!
おめでとうございますー！
Congratulations~!
おめでとうございます。同じ日なんですよ。
Congratulations. It's the same day.
あ、ついに、ついにここで共通点が！
Ah, finally, finally a common point here!
待って待って、あくあ先輩が…あ…
Wait, wait, Aqua-senpai... ah...
実は…衣装がお揃いなんです！
Actually... our outfits are matching!
あ、お揃いだ！
Oh, they're matching!
お揃いだ！
Matching!
ひ、ひも！ひも！
Str-strings! Strings!
ひもついてる！
There are strings!
かわええ！かわええ！
So cute! So cute!
あくすい、あくすい、あくすいちゃんねる！
Aku-Sui, Aku-Sui, Aku-Sui Channel!
湊あくあと星街すいせいがここでおしゃべり…
Minato Aqua and Hoshimachi Suisei are chatting here...
いじめ、いじめが発生してますよ、ねぇ。
Bullying, bullying is happening, hey.
あくすいちゃんねる、お邪魔、あくすい…
Aku-Sui Channel, intruding, Aku-Sui...
アンチ！アンチ！ダメ！絶対ダメ！
Anti! Anti! No! Absolutely no!
超アンチなんだけど。
I'm a total anti right now.
でもさ、トワ様とあくたんさ、記念日が一緒じゃん、記念日が。
But, Towa-sama and Akutan, your anniversaries are the same, right?
そうだよ！当日！
That's right! The same day!
いやいやいや、一緒じゃありません！一緒じゃありません！
No, no, no, they're not the same! They're not!
しかもツインテールも一緒だ！
And even the twin tails are the same!
いやいやいや、出したり引っ込めたりだし、今ちょっとあれだし。
No, no, no, I put them out and tuck them in, and right now they're just...
ほら！しかもどっちもくるくるしてやがる。
Look! And both of them are curly.
お揃いだよ、くるくるだよ。
Matching, curly.
ダメだから！ダメだから！
No way! No way!
待って、3人がなんかさ、共通点ないのかな、私たち。
Wait, isn't there something the three of us have in common?
何だろうね。ちょっと女出そうか、女。
I wonder what. Shall we show some "womanhood"?
女、女、女。
Woman, woman, woman.
ひどい！それ！
That's mean!
女子。いい。
Girls. Good.
いつもなんかね、一歩足りない。でもさ…
Always somehow, a step short. But wait...
…全員メッシュが入ってる、じゃない？
...we all have streaks in our hair, don't we?
すいちゃんは…ちょっと今日は落ちてるんだけど。
Sui-chan is... it's a bit faded today, though.
でもすいちゃんもね、別の衣装だったらインナーカラー入ってるから。
But Sui-chan too, if it were a different outfit, there'd be inner color.
あ、別の衣装ならね。
Ah, if it's a different outfit.
やっぱちょっと、なんかギクシャクしたスターテンでございますけどもね。
As expected, it's a bit of an awkward Startend, though.
ギクシャクだわ。
Awkward indeed.
これからもギクシャクなくね、やっていきたいです。
I want to keep going without the awkwardness.
これからもさ、3人の共通点作ろうね。
Let's keep making things in common for the three of us.
でも次いつ会えるかわからないよ。
But we don't know when we'll meet next.
てかさ、我々も揃ったの久しぶりだし。
I mean, it's been a while since the three of us gathered.
3日ぶり？3日ぶりだから。
Three days? It's been three days.
待って、うちら打ち上げしてないからね、大会終わってから。
Wait, we haven't had an after-party, since the tournament ended.
そう、打ち上げ。でも二人(トワ・あくあ)は…
Right, the after-party. But didn't you two...
…仲良く焼肉行ったとか言ってなかった？
...say you went out for yakiniku together?
待って、あ、二人、二人で行った…
Wait, ah, the two of us, we went together...
ツワトワチャンネルで、ダメでーす、ダメでーす。
It's the Tsuwa-Towa Channel now, no good, no good.
ダメです！もう次の曲行きましょう。アンチがいる状態で。
No good! Let's move to the next song. While there's an anti here.
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
湊あくあ
Minato Aqua
NEXT SONG
ふでペン ~ボールペン~
Fude Pen ~Ballpoint Pen~
ふでペン ぷぷっ
Fude pen, p-p-p
ふるえる ぷぷっ
Trembling, p-p-p
はじめて君へのレター
The first letter to you
ときめきだっしゃー
Heart-pounding, dash!
あふれてだっしゃー
Overflowing, dash!
はみだしちゃうかもね
It might spill over
君の笑顔 想像して
Imagining your smile
いいとこ 見せたくなるよ
I want to show my best side
でもね ツボを 握りしめ
But, clutching the pen-tip
振り向かせてみせる
I'll make you turn around
愛を込めて スラスラとね
With love, smoothly
さあ書き出そう
Now, let's start writing
受け取った君に 幸せが
May happiness find you
つながるように
as you receive it
夢を見せて クルクルとね
Showing dreams, spinning
字が舞い踊る
Letters dance around
がんばれ ふでペン ここまで来たから
Go for it, fude pen, you've come this far
かなり本気よ
I'm quite serious
ふでペン ぷぷっ
Fude pen, p-p-p
無理かも ぷぷっ
It might be impossible, p-p-p
くじけそうになるけれど
I'm about to get discouraged, but
手書きがミッション
Handwriting is the mission
熱いよテンション
High tension
一途 猪突猛進
Single-minded, reckless charge
はみ出たこと 埋める所
Filling in the parts that spilled over
ときどき まるで恋だね
Sometimes, it's just like love
これからも よろしくね
I look forward to our future
ひと言添えて
adding a single word
弾む文字は ピカピカにね
The bouncing letters, all shiny
ほら磨き上げ
Look, polished up
まっすぐ君の 心まで
Straight to your heart
届けばいいな
I hope they reach
走る軌跡 キラキラだね
The running trail is sparkling
ほら乾くまで
Look, until it dries
待ってて 筆で
Wait for me with a brush
ごめんね ボールペンを
Sorry, I'm letting my ballpoint pen...
おやすみさせて
...take a break
君の笑顔 想像して
Imagining your smile
いいとこ 見せたくなるよ
Makes me want to show you my best side
情熱のボールペンを
Grasping my ballpoint pen of passion
握りしめ 振り向かなきゃ
I mustn't look back
愛を込めて ぐるぐると
With all my love, round and round
さあ 書き出そう
Now let's start writing
受け取った 君に 幸せが
So that the happiness will
繋がるように
Connect to you who received it
夢を見せて ぐるぐると
Show me a dream, round and round
違う色 踊る
Different colors dancing
頑張れ 筆で
Go for it, with my brush
ここまで 来たから
Because I've come this far
かなり 本気よ
I'm quite serious
唯〜！今日のライブ最高だったぞ！
Yui~! Today's live was the best!
唯！最高だったぞ！
Yui! It was the best!
練習の甲斐あったな！
The practice paid off!
唯〜！最高だったじゃないか！
Yui~! Wasn't it the best?!
軽音部、唯、バンドやろうよ！バンド！
Light Music Club, Yui, let's start a band! A band!
軽音部だよ軽音部！
It's the Light Music Club, the Light Music Club!
軽音部、軽音部、リッちゃん、軽音部、リッちゃん
Light Music Club, Light Music Club, Ricchan, Light Music Club, Ricchan
え、リッちゃんって誰？
Wait, who's Ricchan?
マリンなんですけど…
It's Marine, but...
船長？
Senchou?
船長なんですけど…リッちゃん、リッちゃんは？
It's Senchou, but... where's Ricchan?
リッちゃんって誰？
Who's Ricchan?
マリンなんですけど…
It's Marine...
俺、俺の名前忘れないでもらっていいですか？
Could you please not forget my name?
ちょっと待って待って待って、さっきまでなんか軽音部ごっこしてたじゃん！
Wait, wait, wait, weren't we just roleplaying the Light Music Club?!
あくあ船長、さっきからさ、ギター、エアギターしすぎて肩がカクカクになっちゃったんだけど
Aqua-senchou, my shoulders are all stiff from doing too much air guitar earlier
エアとか言うな！本気、エアじゃないから！
Don't say air! It's serious, it's not air!
エアじゃなかったの？
It wasn't air?
ちゃんとやってたじゃんか！
I was doing it for real!
弾いてた気分だったんだ…
I felt like I was playing...
いやでもギター持ってる姿あんまりないからさ、これせっかくだから、ちょ、撮りますか？
Well, since we don't often see you with a guitar, shall we take a picture while we're at it?
撮りますか。
Let's do it.
すごい。ちなみに船長、それベースだよ。
Wow. By the way, Senchou, that's a bass.
これベース？！
This is a bass?!
ベースでした…
It was a bass...
これベースだよ、こうやって弾いてるけどベースだよ、こうやってやらないのかな？
That's a bass. You're playing it like this, but it's a bass. Don't you do it like this?
こうだね、こうだね。
Like this, like this.
あ、こうやってやればよかった。
Ah, I should have done it like this.
じゃあちょっとやろうよ、やり損なったから。
Then let's do it a bit, since we missed out.
船長これね、ジャーン、ジャーン。見て、激しいこの首の動き。
Senchou, this is it. *Strum*, *strum*. Look at this intense head movement.
ジャーン、ジャーン。
*Strum*, *strum*.
痛い痛い痛い痛い、さっきから当たってんのよ、ギターが。
Ow, ow, ow, ow, the guitar keeps hitting me.
痛いよ、ぶつかりまくってるっていう。
It hurts, they're constantly clashing.
痛いよ、肩肩が、ボロボロになっちゃう。
It hurts, my shoulders are getting wrecked.
大丈夫？あくあ。当たってる痛いよ。
Are you okay, Aqua? It hurts when it hits.
あ、あ、大丈夫？当た、当たるけど。
Ah, are you okay? It hits, though.
やりみたいだね。あくあ、大丈夫よ。
It's like a spear. Aqua, it's okay.
あくあ傷だらけにするの悲しいな。
It's sad to leave Aqua covered in bruises.
痛い、おかしいだろ。痛い、痛い、怖い怖い怖い怖いって。
It hurts, that's not right. It hurts, it hurts, scary scary scary scary.
あくあ何で離れてくの？！怖いって！寂しいよあくあ！
Aqua, why are you moving away?! You're saying it's scary! I'm lonely, Aqua!
ほら戻って戻って。
Come on, come back, come back.
ねえ、勝手に弾いてる。ねえ船長、ギタリストの才能あるかも。
Hey, you're playing on your own. Hey Senchou, you might have talent as a guitarist.
これベースだよ、ベース。これベースだったわ。
This is a bass, a bass. It was a bass.
どう？何でこの曲選んだの？
How was it? Why did you choose this song?
あのね、何か船長を見るとさ、軽音を思い出すっていうか。
Well, you see, whenever I look at you Senchou, it reminds me of K-ON!
あくあ、それ結構鋭い。
Aqua, that's quite sharp.
鋭い？
Sharp?
船長ね、実はね、本当に軽音とマジ同い…いや、同じ感じで。
Senchou, actually, really the same age as K-ON... no, in the same way.
本当に何か、本当に唯たちと一緒に卒業していったまであるレベルで、一緒に時を過ごしてきたの。
Really, on a level where I practically graduated along with Yui and the others, we spent that time together.
待って、船長の時代って軽音あんの？何これ。
Wait, was K-ON around in Senchou's era? What's this?
何これハート、若いTikTokの。
What's this heart? The young TikTok one.
軽音…あ、あったわ！ふざけんなお前！あるわよ！軽音と一緒に時を過ごしてきたって言ってんだろうが！
K-ON... Ah, it was! Don't mess with me! It was! I told you I spent my time with K-ON!
やってんだろうが！もうずっと手が止まらないんだけど、お前助けて、誰か止めて、右手を止めて。
I'm doing it! My hand won't stop moving, help me, someone stop it, stop my right hand.
や、でもね、せっかくギター持ったから、あくあに、何かギターを使った秘技を教えたいかなと思って。
Well, but since we have guitars, I thought I'd teach Aqua some secret technique using a guitar.
本当ですか？
Really?
ちょっと普通に弾き方ずっとやっててね、新しい弾き方がね、今浮かんできた。
Just keep playing normally, okay? A new way of playing just came to me.
これベースだけどね。
This is a bass, though.
そうこれベース。何度も言うけどさ。じゃあ行きますよ、マリン。秘技！
Yeah, it's a bass. I've said it many times. Okay, here I go, Marine. Secret technique!
はい、走り弾き！
Yes, running-strum!
このまま去っていけるっていう。
And I can just leave like this.
じゃあね、あくあ！4周年おめでとう！
See ya, Aqua! Congrats on your 4th anniversary!
待ってー！
Wait up!
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
湊あくあ
Minato Aqua
NEXT SONG
ハウトゥー世界征服 / 湊あくあ 天音かなた
How-to World Domination / Minato Aqua, Amane Kanata
ハウトゥー世界征服 作曲・作詞：Neru
How-to World Domination | Music & Lyrics: Neru
泣きべそばかりかいてるのはどっちの面
Which one of us is it making a tearful face?
笑われた分だけやり返せ
Give back as much as you were laughed at
今に見てろと手に取った物は
What I picked up, saying "Just you wait"
爆弾やナイフなんてもんじゃないけど
Wasn't anything like a bomb or a knife, but...
一切合切今後どうなったって約束しよう
Let's promise, no matter what happens from here on out
背中の値札を引き剥がせ
Tear off the price tag on your back
廃材みたいな毎日だけど
Every day is like scrap metal, but...
捨てるのはまだ早いだろ
It's too early to throw it all away, isn't it?
今日も 打ち震えながら
Today as well, while trembling
終着駅のホームで
On the platform of the terminal station
明日の僕がまだ待っている
Tomorrow's me is still waiting
わがままで どん欲な 主の御許へ
To the presence of the selfish and greedy master
どうせいっそ願って狂う間がその全てなら
If that's all there is for as long as I'm wishing and going crazy anyway
きっと真似した機械が喋れるぞ
I'm sure a machine that mimics can talk
何だって言いたいんだ、眼に見える前に
I want to say something, before it becomes visible to the eye
心の傷をちょっと癒してくれ
Heal the wounds in my heart a little
あんな空でミサイルが飛ぶのなら
If missiles are flying in that sky
そんなもので幸せを乞うのなら
If you're begging for happiness with things like that
優しい人にならなくちゃ
I have to become a kind person
僕は僕を肯定してけるかな
I wonder if I'll be able to accept myself
ということで！
And so!
かなたん来てくれてありがとう！
Kanatan, thank you for coming!
お邪魔します！
Thank you for having me!
いやー、あくたん、
Man, Akutan,
4周年おめでとうございます！
Congratulations on your 4th anniversary!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
かなたんにお祝いしてもらったの、なんかちょっと嬉しい、ありがとうございます
I'm actually quite happy to have Kanatan celebrate with me, thank you
何々？
What what?
いや、あの、前も僕の誕生日の時に一緒に…
No, well, we were together on my birthday too...
ありがとうございます、そちらもおめでとうございました
Thank you, and congratulations to you as well for that
あの時はですね、MCがなかったんで、
At that time, we didn't have an MC section,
そうっすね。
That's true.
なにげにあの、こうやって喋るのは…
Implicitly, talking like this...
2人きりでは、あの、なんと初めましてということで。
Between just the two of us, well, it's actually the first time.
初めまして！
Nice to meet you!
ども、ども。
Hello, hello.
いやー、僕たち、あの…
Man, we, well...
今回なんで呼んでくれたのかなっていう。
I wonder why you invited me this time.
え、なんかでもね、やっぱあの、かなたんと…
Well, somehow, you know, with Kanatan...
この曲歌いたいなって思ってたんだよね。
I've been wanting to sing this song.
おー、嬉しい！
Oh, I'm glad!
あの、僕たちあの、あまりコラボとかもしてなくてさ。
Well, we haven't really done many collabs.
そうだね、そうだね、あんまりしてない、本当にしてないね！
That's true, that's true, we haven't done many, really haven't!
本当にいつしたんだ最後は？
Really, when was the last time we did?
歌、一緒に歌ってるから、ちょいちょいね。
Since we sing together, we do see each other from time to time.
あー、歌ってみたとかね。
Ah, like in "Utattemita" (cover) videos.
そうそうそう。
Right, right, right.
いっぱい歌ったしね。
We've sung together a lot.
そうそうそう。
Right, right, right.
でも、ほら、最近LINE交換…
But look, we recently exchanged LINE...
したやん
We did it.
ん？
Huh?
LINE交換したやん
We exchanged LINE IDs.
したっけ？
Did we?
したやん、こないだして…
We did, we did it recently and...
もうそれ一回もやり取りしてねーけど
But we haven't messaged each other once.
したっけ？
Did we?
本気で忘れてるんですけどちょっと
Wait, you've seriously forgotten.
ちょっと待って、本当にいつしたっけ？
Wait a second, when did we really do that?
いやしたじゃん！したじゃん！
No, we did! We did!
え？ちょっと待ってくださいよ。いつ、いつしたっけ？
Eh? Please wait. When, when was it?
え、なん、何の時だ？何…
Eh, what, when was it? What...
ここにね、仲介人
There was a mediator here.
お集まりですがいた時に
When everyone was gathered...
あくたんとLINEやってたから「え、僕もー」って言ったら
I was on LINE with Akutan, and when I said "Eh, me too..."
やったわー！
I did it!
本気で忘れてるんですけど、この人…
I completely forgot. This person...
そうだ！
That's right!
この、このMC、3分ぐらいあるって
This, this MC segment is about 3 minutes long.
まだ時間あるんだけど。もっと僕と喋ろうよ。
We still have time. Let's talk more.
これから僕たちの関係性が始まっていくということで
So our relationship is just starting from here.
現時点であくたんの中の僕がどこにいるのかちょっと聞きたいんですけど
I'd like to ask where I stand with Akutan right now.
ここが、あのー、知り合い。
This is, well, "acquaintance".
知り合い、なるほどね。
Acquaintance, I see.
知り合い。
Acquaintance.
仕事仲間。
Work colleague.
友達。
Friend.
大親友。
Best friend.
ちょっと待って、振れ幅すごくない？
Wait, isn't the range a bit too wide?
どこですか？その、間は？間は？間に入れてもいいよ。
Where am I? What about the middle? You can put me in the middle too.
やばい…もうちょっと、だいたい、大親友ね…
Oh boy... more or like, best friend, huh...
大親友。
Best friend.
なんでも相談できる、毎日連絡を取る、大親友。
Someone you can talk to about anything, someone you message every day. Best friend.
んー…
Hmm...
そうですねー。大親友…ということで…
Well... let's go with... best friend.
仕事仲間ー！！
Work colleague!!
ガッ、ガッ。かなたん、時々来るんだよね、こういうパンチ。
Ugh, ugh. Kanatan, you throw these punches sometimes.
パンチ来るんだよ。
You throw punches.
いや、でもこっからね。
No, but from here on.
ま、そうだよね。大親友に近づいていくんで。
Well, that's right. We'll get closer to being best friends.
ぶっちゃけ今の、今は、ま、そうだね。船長の友達の、友達の友達。
To be honest, right now, well... the friend of a friend of Senchou's friend.
あ、でも今年バリにいないからこっからね、やっぱり。
Oh, but we're here now, so from here on.
衣装なんかもね、ちょっとつ、ついに…
Even our outfits, finally...
そう、衣装。なぜか対になっているような色が。
Yes, the outfits. For some reason, the colors seem to complement each other.
すごいよね、これ。ちょっと双子なんで。
It's amazing. We're like twins.
そうなの。で、真逆になっている。
That's right. And they're opposites.
じゃ、最後にあくたん、僕に愛情いっぱい込めて抱きついてもらって終わりにしましょう。
Then finally, Akutan, give me a hug full of love and let's end this.
なんで友達の友達なのに？
Why, when we're just friends of a friend?
そうだよ。ここで友達がいないってことの壁を破るんだ。
That's right. Break the wall of not having friends right here.
おいでー。えーえー、かなたー。
Come here. Hey, hey, Kanata.
あくたーん。
Akutan.
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
湊あくあ
Minato Aqua
NEXT SONG →→
灰色と青
湊あくあ 猫又おかゆ
Haiiro to Ao
Minato Aqua Nekomata Okayu
袖丈が覚束ない夏の終わり
At the end of summer, my sleeve length is uncertain
明け方の電車に揺られて思い出した
Swaying in the early morning train, I remembered
懐かしいあの風景
That nostalgic scenery
たくさんの遠回りを繰り返して
After taking many detours over and over
同じような街並みがただ通り過ぎた
Similar cityscapes just passed by
窓に僕が写ってる
I'm reflected in the window
君は今もあの頃みたいにいるのだろうか
I wonder if you are still like you were back then
ひしゃげて曲がったあの自転車で走り回った
Riding around on that crushed and bent bicycle
馬鹿馬鹿しい綱渡り 膝に滲んだ血
A ridiculous tightrope walk, blood seeping from my knee
今は何だかひどく虚しい
Now, somehow, it feels terribly empty
どれだけ背丈が変わろうとも
No matter how much our heights change
変わらない何かが ありますように
I hope there is something that never changes
くだらない面影に励まされ
Encouraged by trivial memories
今も歌う 今も歌う 今も歌う
I still sing, I still sing, I still sing
ラララ...
La la la...
どこからか震えたあの瞬間に
At that moment when I started trembling from somewhere
もう一度出会えたらいいと強く思う
I strongly hope we can meet once again
忘れることはないんだ
I will never forget
君は今もあの頃みたいに居るのだろうか
Are you still the same as you were back then?
靴を片方茂みに落として探し回った
I dropped one shoe in the bushes and searched all around for it
何があろうと僕らはきっとうまくいくと
That no matter what happens, we'll surely be fine
無邪気に笑えた日々を覚えてる
I remember the days when we could laugh innocently
どれだけ無様に傷つくことも
No matter how awkwardly we get hurt
終わらない毎日に花束を
Flowers for the days that never end
くだらない面影を追いかけて
Chasing after worthless memories
今も歌う 今も歌う 今も歌う
I'm still singing, still singing, still singing
La la la...
朝日が昇る前の欠けた月も
Even the waning moon before the sunrise
君もどこかで見てるのかな
I wonder if you're watching it from somewhere too
何故か今日は何でもないのに胸が痛くて
For some reason, my chest hurts today even though nothing happened
滲む顔 霞む色
Blurred face, hazy colors
今さら悲しいと叫ぶには
To cry out that I'm sad after all this time
あまりにすべてが遅すぎたかな
Everything might have been just too late
もう一度初めから歩けるなら
If I could walk from the beginning once more
すれ違うように君に会いたい
I want to meet you as if we're passing each other by
どれだけ背丈が変わろうとも
No matter how much our heights change
変わらない何かが ありますように
I hope there's something that remains unchanged
くだらない面影に励まされ
Encouraged by worthless memories
今も歌う 今も歌う 今も歌う
I'm still singing, still singing, still singing
La la la...
朝日が昇る前の欠けた月も
Even the waning moon before the sunrise
君もどこかで見てるのかな
I wonder if you're watching it from somewhere too
何もないと笑える朝日がきて
The morning sun comes, laughing that there's nothing wrong
始まりは青い色
The beginning is the color blue
あくあ、4周年おめでとう！
Aqua, congratulations on your 4th anniversary!
ありがとう おかゆー！
Thank you, Okayu-!
ありがとうー
Thank you-
ということでおかゆが来てくれました！
And so, Okayu has come to visit!
イエーイ 今回もね、呼んでくれてありがとう
Yay! Thanks for inviting me again this time.
いやいやいや。おかゆさんとはね、やっぱり運命共同体ですから。
No no no. After all, you and I are a "destiny-sharing couple."
あ、そうだったんだ。
Oh, is that so?
そうですよ、呼ばないわけがないわけです。
Yes, there's no way I wouldn't invite you.
運命共同体になったつもりは微塵もなかったけどね。
I didn't have the slightest intention of becoming a "destiny-sharing couple" though.
なんで！そんなことないでしょ！あくおかは永遠だよ！
Why! That's not true! AkuOka is forever!
永遠。
Forever.
あくおかは永遠！
AkuOka is forever!
そうだったんだ。
Is that so.
そうだったんだってなに！他人事じゃん！
What do you mean, "is that so"! You're acting like it's someone else's business!
そうだったんだ。
Is that so.
いや、あくおかはね、むしろなんか、全然そういうのとはかけ離れてる存在だとばかり思ってたけどね。
Well, I thought AkuOka was an existence that was completely far removed from that kind of thing.
いやいや、私たちはSとMで繋がってるんで、磁石のように。そう。
No no, we are connected by S and M, like magnets. Yes.
ちょっとキモいね。
That's a bit gross.
なんで！なんで！なんで！
Why! Why! Why!
あくあがSってこと？
Does that mean Aqua is the S?
そうだよ、でおかゆ、え、おかゆがM。
Yes, and Okayu, uh, Okayu is the M.
逆でもいいよ。
Or vice versa is fine too.
なんかちょっと怖い。鳥肌立ってきた。
That's a bit scary. I'm getting goosebumps.
なんでさ！なんでだよ！
Why! Why is that!
まあ、まあまあ、ちょっとこれは気持ち悪くなっちゃうからさ。
Well, well, this is starting to get weird, so...
灰色と青ね、エモかったね。
Grey and Blue was really emotional, wasn't it?
気持ち悪くないけどね、大切だけどね。
It's not weird, it's precious though.
いや良かったね。
Yeah, it was good.
めちゃめちゃ良かったよ。
It was really great.
やっぱりちょっと、今年のあくおかは、2022年バージョンは、ちょっとエモ路線で行きたいんですよ。
I really want this year's AkuOka, the 2022 version, to go for a more emotional style.
あー、湊プロデューサー的には、あくおかはエモ。
Ah, from the perspective of Producer Minato, AkuOka is emotional.
はい。
Yes.
エモいんだ。
It's emotional.
エモです。
It is emotional.
エモしかないですよ、やっぱ。
There's nothing but emotion, after all.
いや、僕たちどっちかっていうとギャグみたいなとこない？
Wait, aren't we more like a gag duo?
ないよ！
No, we're not!
私たちは永遠ラブストーリー...
We are an eternal love story...
...コメディ。
...comedy.
いやいやいや、いや、もうコメディ言うてもうてますやん。
No, no, no! You just said "comedy"!
言うてもうてますやん。
You just said it.
いやいやいや。
No, no, no.
オフィスラブ。
Office love.
オフィスラブ。そう。
Office love. Right.
だから、この、今日はね、おかゆが来てくれたから...
So, today, since Okayu came here...
...このステージでちょっと二人きりで...
...on this stage, just the two of us...
...最後に星を眺めながらエンディングっていうね。
...looking at the stars for the ending.
あ、そうだそうだ、そろそろね、みんなのこと呼びに行かなきゃいけない時間じゃん。
Oh, right. It's about time I go call everyone.
いやいやちょっと待って待って待って。空を見ながら、星を眺めてエンディングっていうね。
Wait, wait, wait, wait! Looking at the sky, watching the stars for the ending!
おーい、みんなー、そろそろ準備の時間だよー！
Hey, everyone! It's almost time for prep!
待ってー！ おかゆー！
Wait! Okayu!
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
常闇トワ
Tokoyami Towa
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
湊あくあ
Minato Aqua
NEXT SONG
サイレントマジョリティー
Silent Majority
湊あくあ 星街すいせい 常闇トワ 宝鐘マリン 天音かなた 猫又おかゆ
Minato Aqua, Hoshimachi Suisei, Tokoyami Towa, Houshou Marine, Amane Kanata, Nekomata Okayu
人があふれた交差点を
At a crowded intersection
どこへ行く
Where are you going?
押し流され
Being pushed along
似たような服を着て
Wearing similar clothes
似たような表情で
With similar expressions
群れの中に紛れるように
As if to blend into the crowd
歩いてる
Walking
疑わずに
Without doubting
誰かと違うことに
About being different from someone else
何をためらうのだろう
What are you hesitating for?
先行く人が振り返り
The person ahead looks back
列を乱すなと
And says "Don't break the line"
ルールを説くけど
Preaching the rules
その目は死んでいる
But those eyes are dead
君は君らしく生きて行く自由があるんだ
You have the freedom to live as yourself
大人たちに支配されるな
Don't be controlled by adults
初めからそうあきらめてしまったら
If you give up from the start like that
僕らは何のために生まれたのか？
What were we born for?
夢を見ることは時には孤独にもなるよ
Dreaming can sometimes make you lonely
誰もいない道を進むんだ
Move forward on the path where no one is
この世界は群れていても始まらない
This world won't start even if you're in a crowd
Yesでいいのか？ サイレントマジョリティー
Is "Yes" okay? Silent Majority
どこかの国の大統領が
The president of some country
言っていた
Was saying
賛成か反対か
Whether you're for or against
声を上げない者たちは
Those who don't raise their voices
賛成していると言っている
Are saying they agree
選べる事こそ大事なんだ
Being able to choose is what's important
人に任せるな
Don't leave it to others
行動しなければ
If you don't take action
Noとも伝わらない
Your "No" won't be conveyed either
君は君らしくやりたいことをやるだけさ
You just do what you want to do as yourself
どぶ鼠に成り下がるな
Don't degrade yourself to a sewer rat
ここにいる人の数だけ道はある
There are as many paths as there are people here
自分の夢の方に歩けばいい
Just walk towards your own dream
見栄やプライドの鎖に繋がれたような
Like being chained by vanity and pride
つまらない大人は置いて行け
Leave those boring adults behind
さあ未来は君たちのためにある
Now the future is there for you
NOと言いなよ サイレントマジョリティー
Say "No", Silent Majority
誰かの後 ついて行けば
If you follow someone else
傷つかないけど
You won't get hurt
その群れが
But that crowd
総意だと
If it's the consensus
ひとまとめにされる
You'll be lumped together
君は君らしく生きて行く自由があるんだ
You have the freedom to live as yourself
大人たちに支配されるな
Don't be controlled by adults
初めからそうあきらめてしまったら
If you give up from the start like that
僕らは何のために生まれたのか？
What were we born for?
夢を見ることは時には孤独にもなるよ
Dreaming can sometimes make you lonely
誰もいない道を進むんだ
Move forward on the path where no one is
この世界は群れていても始まらない
This world won't start even if you're in a crowd
Yesでいいのか？ サイレントマジョリティー
Is "Yes" okay? Silent Majority
Silent Majority...
海想列車 本の少しだけ
Reminiscing Train, just for a little bit,
夢の中で
within a dream,
ゆらゆら 揺られて
swaying back and forth,
波に包まれていたい
I want to be enveloped by the waves.
海想列車
作詞・作曲：40mP
Reminiscing Train
Lyrics/Composition: 40mP
夢を見てた
I was dreaming,
あの頃の夢を
dreaming of those days.
おくびょうだった
I was a coward,
どこにもいけなかった
I couldn't go anywhere.
変わりたくて
Wanting to change,
電車に乗り込んだ
I boarded the train.
この世界で 1 枚だけの切符
A one-of-a-kind ticket in this world.
路線図も時刻表も
With no route map or timetable,
今は空白だけど
it's currently blank, but
窓の向こうには
beyond the window is
青より青い水平線
a horizon bluer than blue.
海想列車 本の少しだけ
Reminiscing Train, just for a little bit,
遠い景色へと
towards a distant scenery.
走り出した夢はもう止まらない
The dream that has started running won't stop anymore.
正解なんて考えてみても 分からないから
Because even if I try thinking about the right answer, I won't know it.
目の前に
Right before my eyes,
広がるこの景色を見ていたい
I want to keep looking at this scenery spreading out.
夢を見てた
I was dreaming,
あの頃の夢を
dreaming of those days.
一人じゃきっと ここまで来れなかった
I'm sure I couldn't have come this far alone.
途中の駅で
At a station along the way,
降りたその時にも
even when I got off,
君がいつもそばにいてくれた
you were always there by my side.
「ごめんね」も「ありがとう」も
Both "I'm sorry" and "thank you",
まだ言い足りないよ
I still haven't said them enough.
私のペースで
At my own pace,
不器用なりに伝えていくから
I'll keep conveying them in my own clumsy way.
みんなが応援してくれたから 4 年間もこのステージに立ててます。
Because everyone supported me, I've been able to stand on this stage for 4 years.
これからも一緒にいろんな景色見に行こうね！
Let's go see many more sights together from now on!
感傷を走り抜け
Run through the sentimentality,
まだ知らない世界へ
towards a world I don't know yet.
空白の路線図は
The blank route map
色を纏って作り上げていく
will take on colors as I build it up.
海想列車 夢から覚めた
Reminiscing Train, I woke up from a dream.
懐かしくて
It's nostalgic,
変わらない思いをそっと抱きしめた
and I softly embraced my unchanging feelings.
笑い合って 手を取り合って 同じ時を過ごした
We laughed together, held hands, and spent the same time together.
君と これからもずっと
With you, forever more.
海想列車 もう怖くはない
Reminiscing Train, I'm not afraid anymore.
夢中で駆け抜けた日々は
The days I ran through in a daze
夢じゃないから
weren't a dream.
世界なんて 相変わらず まだ分からないけど
I still don't really understand the world as usual, but
目の前に
Right before my eyes,
広がるこの景色を見ていたい
I want to keep looking at this scenery spreading out.
君と一緒に この景色を見ていたい
I want to keep looking at this scenery together with you.
ということで、ありがとうございましたー！
And so, thank you very much!
えー、『海想列車』でした。ありがとうございました。
Um, that was 'Kaisou Ressha'. Thank you very much.
『海想列車』はね、3周年の記念で、ちょっとね、あの、出させていただいた曲なんだけど...
'Kaisou Ressha' is a song I released for my 3rd anniversary...
今回、4周年ということで。
And now, it's my 4th anniversary.
今回はちょっと、「あくあ色ふぇすてぃばる。」ということで。
So this time, for 'Aqua-Iro Festival'...
ちょっとですね、たくさんのゲストさんを呼んで...
I invited many guests...
多分ゲストさんを呼ぶのは、結構こんなにたくさんのゲストを呼ぶのは、私のライブでは、なにげ初めてかな？
It might actually be the first time I've invited so many guests for one of my concerts.
多分。多分です。
Probably. I think so.
で、まあ4周年ということで、今回はちょっと、あの、4周年だし、やっぱ私、先輩だし...
And since it's my 4th anniversary, and I'm a senior now...
ちょっといろんな人を呼んで、ちょっとわちゃわちゃ、フェスティバルみたいに、わちゃわちゃできたらいいなっていうことで。
I wanted to invite various people and have a lively, festival-like time together.
ちょっとね、いつも歌わないようなかっこいい曲とか、今回歌わせていただきました。ありがとう！
I also got to sing some cool songs that I don't usually sing. Thank you!
いや、みんなとね、絡めたのもすごい楽しかった！
Man, it was so much fun interacting with everyone!
みんなはね、どうだった？どれが良かったですか？
How about you all? Which part did you like best?
ということで。今からね、これちょっと「何があんの？」って話だと思うんですが。
Anyway. I'm sure you're wondering what's next.
なんとここで...新曲披露させていただきます！
Well, right now... I'm going to perform a new song!
うぉー！新曲です！
Whoo! A new song!
まあね、えーと、8月8日。本当はね、8月8日が、私のデビュー日、4周年記念なんですが。
Actually, August 8th was my debut date and 4th anniversary.
えー、今回はね、その8月8日に先行ストリーミング配信が開始された新曲、『未だ、青い』、初披露！ライブ初披露！
And today, I'll be performing the new song 'Imada, Aoi' for the first time! Its live debut!
前代未聞の...えーっと、初披露。
An unprecedented... um, first performance.
前代未聞じゃないか。全然前代未聞じゃないわ。
Wait, not unprecedented. It's not unprecedented at all.
なんか突っ込みがいないとちょっと、なんか寂しいね。一人で喋ってちょっと寂しいな。
It's a bit lonely without someone to call me out. Talking all by myself is lonely.
です！ということで、今回は新曲を披露させていただこうかなと思っておるのですが...
Yeah! So, I'm about to perform the new song...
この配信の後に、なんと新曲『未だ、青い』、MVが上がります！
And after this stream, the music video for 'Imada, Aoi' will be released!
マジで、マジで、すごい！マジですごいので、本当にみんな是非この配信終わったらチェックしてください。お願いします。
It's seriously, seriously amazing! It's so good, so please check it out after the stream. I'm begging you.
え、マジですごいよ。みんなね、クオリティにびっくりすると思う。
No, really, it's incredible. You'll all be shocked by the quality.
「え、あくたん、こんなクオリティをまさか無料で見てしまっていいんですか！？」ってなる気がします。
I feel like you'll be like, "Wait, Akutan, is it okay to watch something this high quality for free!?"
ので、ぜひ見てください。お願いします！そして、えー...
So please watch it. I'm counting on you! And, uh...
こちらも8月8日の、えーっと、4周年の記念で、ご紹介はしたんですが...
Also related to the 4th anniversary on August 8th, I've mentioned this before, but...
グッズが、4周年記念グッズも発売しておりますので。
My 4th anniversary commemorative goods are now on sale.
よかったら概要欄の方で購入ができるので、チェックしてーくーだーさい。お願いします。
You can buy them from the link in the description, so please check them out. Please!
色々ね、こういうのとか、こういうのとか、グッズになってます。お願いします。
Various things like this and that have been made into goods. Thank you.
ということで、じゃあ早速、新曲の方を歌わせていただきたいと思います。
Anyway, without further ado, I'd like to sing the new song now.
それでは聴いてください、『未だ、青い』。
Please listen: 'Imada, Aoi'.
未だ、青い
作詞・作曲：じん
Still Blue
Lyrics & Composition: Jin
風一つ 染まっていく音を たなびかせて
A single breeze, trailing the sound of colors blending
流れ出す 朝焼けの空を 飛んでいく
Flying through the sky as the morning glow begins to flow
聞こえた 震えてる声の君は誰だろう
I heard it—who are you, with that trembling voice?
何故かな 会いたくなったんだ 会えるのかな
For some reason, I wanted to meet you. Will I be able to?
夢一つ 鞄のポケットに忍ばせて
Hiding a single dream in my bag's pocket
征く一つ 始まりの朝に 遠く響く
Going forth alone, echoing far into the morning of beginnings
思い出す 結んだ指に残った温度は
I remember the warmth that lingered on our entwined fingers
今もまだ 青く残ってる 汗のまま
It's still there even now, remaining blue, just like the sweat
「鳥や雲じゃないから 飛んでいくのは無理だね」
'Since we're not birds or clouds, flying is impossible, isn't it?'
それだったら 歩き出してみよう
If that's the case, let's start walking
そうやって 描いた今日を 通り越して
And like that, passing through the 'today' we drew
明日はもっと 君のそばへ
Tomorrow, I'll be even closer to you
前へ そう前へ
Forward, yes, forward
少しずつ進んでいく
Moving forward little by little
一歩 五十歩 百歩 踏み出して
One step, fifty steps, a hundred steps, taking a leap
揺らめいている君が
You, who are wavering
青く滲む 青く滲む 綺麗に
Bleed into blue, bleed into blue, beautifully
会いに行く 会いに行こう 今すぐ
I'm coming to see you, let's go see you, right now
波白く さざめく音に 耳を立てて
Whiting waves, listening to the rustling sound
赤く、青く、夕映えの空 昇る星
Red, blue, the twilight sky, the rising stars
不思議と 不安な旅も 怖くないから
Strangely, even an uncertain journey isn't scary
手を振って 俯かないように 歩いていく
Waving my hand, walking so as not to look down
「憧れても、願っても 誰にもなれないな」
"Even if I admire, even if I wish, I can't become anyone else"
それだったら 自分になってみよう
In that case, let's try being myself
そうやって
That's how
目指した今日を 飛び越えて
Leaping over the today I aimed for
明日はきっと 会えるから
Because I'm sure we can meet tomorrow
じゃあね、そうしたらね、一緒に 何を話そう
Well then, in that case, what shall we talk about together?
一歩 五十歩 百歩 重ね合って
One step, fifty steps, a hundred steps, overlapping
紡いでいく時間が 溶けていく 溶けていく
The time we spin is melting, melting away
それでも いつかは 夢が 終わるなら
Even so, if the dream must end someday
それでも良いかな 君がいるんなら
I guess that's okay, if you are here
世界の中で 出会えた君が 理由になったら
If you, whom I met in this world, become my reason
それでも良いよね
Then it would be alright, wouldn't it?
一人の今日を 飛び越えて
Leaping over my solitary today
描いた今日を 通り越して
Going past the today I drew
明日はもっと 君のそばへ
Tomorrow, I'll be even closer to you
前へ そう前へ
Forward, yes, forward
少しずつ進めよ
Let's move forward little by little
一歩 五百歩 千歩 繰り返して
One step, five hundred steps, a thousand steps, repeating
指に触れる君が
You, whom my fingers touch
青く滲む 青く滲む 綺麗に
Bleed into blue, bleed into blue, beautifully
いつまでも そばにいて 良いかな
Can I stay by your side forever?
湊あくあ 活動4周年記念 8月8日 販売開始
Minato Aqua 4th Anniversary Celebration - Sales start August 8th
活動4周年記念フルセット / 記念グッズ3種
4th Anniversary Celebration Full Set / 3 types of commemorative goods
湊あくあ「未だ、青い」 ダウンロード＆ストリーミング配信中！
Minato Aqua 'Mada, Aoi' - Now available for download and streaming!
あくありうむ。 完全生産限定版 Hololive Official Edition
AQUARIUM Limited Edition - Hololive Official Edition
あくありうむ。 店舗特典 / 描き下ろしアイテム
AQUARIUM Store Bonuses / Original illustrated items